<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMP90007 Tutorial - Yiran Ruan</title>
    <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on COMP90007 Tutorial - Yiran Ruan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 19:20:47 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yiranruan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial_week9</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 19:20:47 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week9/</guid>
      <description>This is tutorial slides for week9 ​ Sorry for the late update.
​ In this week, we have talked about deadlock, 3-way handshake and 2-army problems. Due to no solution for 2-army problems as for now, both 2-way handshake and 3-way handshake have risk to encouneter deadlock. To solve this problem, we use connection release as a example, to show you how important timer is in our system. Timer would set a time and expected to receive reply during this period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorail_week8</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 22:55:21 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week8/</guid>
      <description>This is tutorial slides for week8 ​ In this week, we have discussed about Aggregation of IP addresses. Then we talked about one method to find correct network that one IP address belongs to.
​ In terms of routing algorithms. There are two categroies. One is non-adaptive algorithm. Routers would calculate the next hop when the network is booted. Another one is adaptive algorithm, which would make desicions depending on information collected from the environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial_week7</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:48:14 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week7/</guid>
      <description>This is tutorial slides for week7 ​ In this week, we have discussed about MACA protocol, IP address (mainly about prefix and subnetmask) and fragmentation.
​ MACA, which is an wonderful protocol to help us aviod collisions withour carrier sense medium. The basic idea is that for the sender to stimulate the receiver into outputting a short frame, so stations nearby can detect this transmission and avoid transmitting for the duration of the upcoming (large) data frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial_week6</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 13:42:11 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week6/</guid>
      <description>This is tutorial slides for week6 ​ In this week, we have discussed about several protocols that we used in Data Link layer and a brief introduction about IP address.
​ The first protocol is stop-and-wait. It is pretty simple. The sender sends one frame and then waits for an acknowledgement before proceeding.
​ Then we talked about CRC, one kind of the checksum that we used in data link layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial_week5</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 08:51:19 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week5/</guid>
      <description>This is tutorial slides for week5 ​ Here is the slides. More info would be updated later. Have fun with your project.
Cheers,
Yiran Ruan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial_week4</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 14:11:13 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week4/</guid>
      <description>This is tutorial slides for week4 ​ The first thing that we discussed in this week is two important theorems, Nyquist&amp;rsquo;s and Shannon&amp;rsquo;s theorem, in physical layer. The main difference between them is Nyquist&amp;rsquo;s theorem assums the channel that we used to transform data is noise-less while the Shannon&amp;rsquo;s theorem is only used for a noisy channel. They both have two components in their formula, bandwidth and levels of signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial_week3</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 21:37:47 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week3/</guid>
      <description>This is tutorial slides for week3 ​ In this week, we have compared the properties between OSI model and TCP/IP model. They both have a similar stacking protocol achitecture, which holds advantages on flexibility and information hiding (content in week2). In terms of differences, OSI model has a good distinguish between Service, Protocol and Interface. In the meanwhile, TCP/IP doesn&amp;rsquo;t.
​ Service defines what the process does, but not how entities above it access it or how the layer works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial_week2</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 02:06:52 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/tutorial_week2/</guid>
      <description>This is tutorial for week2 ​ In week 2, we have learned how to use Wireshark and wget to test the network
​ We simply introduced IP address, three-way handshake, overhead and layer achetechture.
​ Hope you have fun with this subject and my tutorial.
​ This is my slides.
Cheers,
Yiran Ruan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important notices about COMP90007 tutorial</title>
      <link>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 21:41:36 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiranruan.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Notices about COMP90007 tutorial Hi students,
​ Welcome to my repository and thank you to come my tutorials.
​ I am glad if you like my tutorials.
​ Here is the tutorial slides for each week. Feel free to download it. And please give me a star if you like it LOL. I will maintain this GitHub repository continually. You could watch it and if you found any problems in my slides, you are welcome to start a new issues here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>